Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Copper engraving plates of English personalities
1794-1818
OSB MSS 160
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
Richardson, William, active 1778-1815
Godefroy, Jean, 1771-1839
Grave, Robert, 1768-1825
Marshall, William, active 1617-1650
Smith, N. (Nathaniel), 1738?-1809
Trotter, Thomas, 1756-1803
Great Britain -- History -- Civil War, 1642-1649 -- Pictorial works; Copper engravings (visual works); Line engravings (prints); Godefroy, Jean, 1771-1839; Grave, Robert, 1768-1825; Herbert of Cherbury, Edward Herbert, Baron, 1583-1648 -- Portraits; Herrick, Robert, 1591-1674 -- Portraits; Herst, Richard, -1628 -- Portraits; Hewling, Benjamin, 1663-1685 -- Portraits; Hewson, John, -1662 -- Portraits; Heywood, John, 1497?-1580? -- Portraits; Hicks, William, 1621-1660 -- Portraits; Hill, Emery, -1677 -- Portraits; Hoddesdon, John, active 1650 -- Portraits; Holland, Henry Rich, Earl of, 1590-1649 -- Portraits; Holland, Hezekiah, active 1638-1661 -- Portraits; Holles, Frescheville, Sir, 1642-1672 -- Portraits; Hudson, Jeffrey, 1619-1681 -- Portraits; James, King of England, I, 1566-1625 -- Portraits; Marshall, William, active 1617-1650; Nicholas, Edward, Sir, 1593-1669 -- Portraits; Okey, John, -1662 -- Portraits; Oxburgh, Henry, -1716 -- Portraits; Oxman, William, -1661 -- Portraits; Paris, Matthew, 1200-1259 -- Portraits; Pattison, William, 1706-1727 -- Portraits; Paul, William, 1678-1716 -- Portraits; Pecke, Thomas, 1637- -- Portraits; Pendrell, William, 1609-1700 -- Portraits; Perwich, Susanna, 1636-1661 -- Portraits; Pirckheimer, Willibald, 1470-1530 -- Portraits; Richardson, William, active 1778-1815; Smith, N. (Nathaniel), 1738?-1809; Somerset, William Seymour, Duke of, 1588-1660 -- Portraits; Trotter, Thomas, 1756-1803; B. Whittow & Son; Pontifex & Co
- Herbert of Cherbury, Edward Herbert, Baron, 1583-1648, circa 1795; 1 line engraving, 8.1 centimeters by 5.8 centimeters, on a copper plate, 15.8 centimeters by 11.9 centimeters, and 1 print, 8.2 cenitmeters by 8.9 mounted on a sheet, 12.6 centimeters by 10.2 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General
  Published by William Richardson after Wenceslaus Hollar (1607-1677)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: B.W. Probably B. Whittow & Son
- Herrick, Robert, 1591-1674, undated; 1 line engraving, 17 centimeters by 9.5 centimeters, on a copper plate, 18 centimeters by 11.4 centimeters, and 1 print, 21.5 centimeters x 14.6 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Published by William Richardson after an engraving by William Marshall (active 1617-1650)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: B. Whittow & Son, 31 Shoe Lane, Holborn London
  Inscription in engraving in Latin
- Herst, Richard, circa 1796; 1 line engraving, 15.7 centimeters by 9.5 centimeters, on a copper plate, 19.7 centimeters by 11.5 centimeters, and 1 print, 28.2 centimeters by 21.1 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Engraved or published by G. Barrett
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: B. Whittow & Son. No. 31 Shoe Lane, Holborn London
  Scope and Contents
  Accompanied by plate wrapper with imprint: Herst, Richard. Engraved by G. Barrett. A Catholic suspected of harbouring priests. A warrant was issued to apprehend him as a recusant, and in a scuffle that took place on of the officers was killed. Herst escaped, but came forward to take his trial, and was found guilty as accessory to the murder, and executed 26th August, 1628.
- Hewling, Benjamin, undated; 1 line engraving, 16.2 centimeters by 11.6 centimeters, on a copper plate, 20.4 centimeters bu 12.6 centimeters, and 1 print, 21.7 centimeters by 13.3 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: G. Harris. 31 Shoe Lane, London
- Hewson, John, died 1662, undated; 1 line engraving, 12.8 centimeters by 7.8 centimeters, on a copper plate, 17 centimeters by 10.8 centimeters, and 1 print, 26.4 centimeters by 18.1 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: Pontifex & Co 22 Lisle Street, Soho, London
- Heywood, John, 1497?-1580?, circa 1799; 1 line engraving, 17.7 centimeters by 11.4 centimeters, on a copper plate, 19.6 centimeters by 14.2 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Published by William Richardson probably after a woodcut by an unidentified artist
- Hicks, William, 1621-1660, circa 1798; 1 line engraving, 14.1 centimeters by 9.4 centimeters, on a copper plate, 19.6 centimeters by 14.2 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Published by William Richardson after David Loggan (1634-1692)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: Large
- Hill, Emery, died 1677, 1794; 1 line engraving, 15.3 centimeters by 10.1 centimeters, on a copper plate, 17.8 centimeters by 11.4 centimeters, and 1 print, 19.1 centimeters by 12.1 centimeters mounted on a sheet, 27.7 centimeters by 19.9 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Engraved by Thomas Trotter (circa 1750-1803)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: Pontifex. No. 47 Shoe Lane, London
- Hoddesdon, John, circa 1632–1659, undated; 1 line engraving, 15.3 centimeters by 9.1 centimeters, on a copper plate, 16.6 centimeters by 12.1 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Engraved by Thomas Cross (active 1644-1682)
  Accompanied by wrapper with inscription: Hoddesdon, John, In the eighteenth year of his age. From an engraving by T. Cross. Author of "Sion and Parnassus; or, Epigrams on several Texts of the Old and New Testament," 1650, 8vo, to which this portrait is prefixed.
- Holland, Henry Rich, Earl of, 1590-1649, 1796; 1 line engraving, 14.1 centimeters by 9.9 centimeters, on a copper plate, 19.5 centimeters by 15.7 centimeters, and 2 prints, 27.9 centimeters by 20.8 centimeters and smaller (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Engraved by Jean Godefroy (1771-1839) after Samuel Cooper (1609-1672)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: Pontifex No. 47 Shoe Lane
- Holland, Hezekiah, active 1638-1661, 1812; 1 line engraving, 15.1 centimeters by 10.4 centimeters, on a copper plate, 18 centimeters by 13.3 centimeters, and 1 print, 25.2 centimeters by 15.1 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: Will & Russ. Pontifex & Comp. Nos. 46, 47 & 48 Shoe Lane London
- Holles, Frescheville, Sir, 1642-1672, circa 1802; 1 line engraving, 14.9 centimeters by 11.1 centimeters, on a copper plate, 16.6 centimeters by 14.1 centimeters, and 1 print, 27.1 centimeters by 18.5 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Engraved title: Sr. Tretswell Hollis
  Published by William Richardson after Sir Peter Lely (1618-1680)
- Hudson, Jeffrey, 1619-1681, undated; 1 line engraving, 13.3 centimeters by 10.6 centimeters, on a copper plate, 18.5 centimeters by 14.5 centimeters, and 1 print, 22.1 centimeters by 14.3 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: Jones
- James I, King of England, 1566-1625, circa 1793; 1 line and stipple engraving, 21.4 centimeters by 17.4 centimeters, on a copper plate, 22.8 centimeters by 17.6 centimeters (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Published by Nathaniel Smith (1738?-1809)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: Jones & Pontifex No. 47 Shoe Lane
- Nicholas, Edward, Sir, 1593-1669, 1818; 1 line engraving, 24.6 centimeters by 13.2 centimeters, on a copper plate, 30.5 centimeters by 24.2 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 15)
  After Peter Lely (1618-1680)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: T. Large. 15 Little New Street, Shoe Lane
- Okey, John, died 1662, undated; 1 line engraving, 13.5 centimeters by 5.6 centimeters, on a copper plate, 16.5 centimeters by 10.4 centimeters, and 1 print, 24.5 centimeters by 20.6 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: G. Harris. No. 31 Shoe Lane
- Oxburgh, Henry, died 1716, undated; 1 line engraving, 14.9 centimeters by 10 centimeters, on a copper plate, 25.4 centimeters by 15.2 centimeters, and 1 print, 27.9 centimeters by 21.9 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: T. Large. Little New St. Shoe Lane
- Oxman or Orsingham, William, undated; 1 line engraving, 18.4 centimeters by 11.6 centimeters, on a copper plate, 24.4 centimeters by 16.7 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Paris, Matthew, 1200-1259, undated; 1 line engraving, 16.7 centimeters by 9.7 centimeters, on a copper plate, 20.2 centimeters by 12.2 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: B. Whittow & Son, 43 Shoe Lane
- Pattison, William, 1706-1727, undated; 1 line engraving, 16.0 centimeters by 10.2 centimeters, on a copper plate, 25.4 centimeters by 15.2 centimeters, and 1 print, 28.1 cenitmeters by 19.9 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Engraved by Robert Grave (1768-1825)
- Paul, William, 1678-1716, undated; 1 line engraving, 17.6 centimeters by 11.6 centimeters, on a copper plate, 25.5 centimeters by 15.6 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: Shafe. Little Moorfields London
- Pecke, Thomas, born 1637, circa 1794; 1 line engraving, 13.4 centimeters by 9.9 centimeters, on a copper plate, 15.5 centimeters by 10.6 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Published by William Richardson
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: B. Whittow. 43 Shoe Lane
  Etching on verso: 214
- Penderel, William, circa 1808; 1 line engraving, 12.4 centimeters by 9.9 centimeters, on a copper plate, 19.6 centimeters by 15.2 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Identified by inscription on plate as William Pendrill
  Copper plate maker's mark on verso: Whittow & Harris. No. 31 Shoe Lane
- Perwich, Susanna, 1636-1661, 1794; 1 line engraving, 14.4 centimeters by 12.6 centimeters, on a copper plate, 17.3 centimeters by 13.3 centimeters, and 1 print, 24.1 cenitmeters by 14.1 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Published by William Richardson after P. Rogerson (active circa 1661)
- Pirckheimer, Willibald, 1470-1530, undated; 1 line engraving, 8.9 centimeters by 8.1 centimeters, on a copper plate, 12.8 centimeters by 11.7 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Engraved by an unidentified artist after a medal by Peter Vischer (1487-1528) after a draft by Albrecht Dürer (1471-1528)
- Somerset, William Seymour, Duke of, 1588-1660, circa 1798; 1 line engraving, 8.3 centimeters by 5.4 centimeters, on a copper plate, 14.3 centimeters by 11.6 centimeters (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Accompanied by wrapper with inscription: Hertford, Wm. Symour, Marquis of, Afterwards Duke of Somerset. From a print by Hollar. Second son of Ed. L. Beauchamp and Honora Rogers; born September, 1588. Secretly married to Lady Arabella Stuart in 1610 after her death in prison, 27th September, 1615, he married lady Franci Devereux, in 1617. Succeeded as Earl of Hertford, 1621. He fought gallantly for teh King, and even offered his life to save his master; and was one of the four noblemen who bore him to the grave. K.G. at the Restoration; and Duke of Somerset by reversal of his grandfather's attainder. Died October, 1660.